<resources>
    <string name="app_name">ScrollBar</string>
    <string name="textview">Java is an Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) structure.
...
Java is a class-based programming language.
Java technology is used for developing both, applets and applications.
Provides an easy to use: ...
Provides an interpreted environment: ...
Loads classes dynamically, in other words when they are actually needed.
    Java Concept

Sun Microsystems created the Java language.  Java is a case-sensitive programming language, like C++.  Java is an Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) structure.  Java is a class-based programming language.
Java technology is used for developing both, applets and applications.

Provides an easy to use:
Avoids many of the pitfalls of other languages
Bing object-oriented
Enables code streamlining

Provides an interpreted environment:
Improved speed of development.
Code portability.

Loads classes dynamically, in other words when they are actually needed.

Supports changing programs dynamically, during runtime, by loading classes from a distinct source.

Furnishes better security.

Enables use of more than one thread of activity.

The Java Virtual Machine (JVM).

Garbage collection.

The Java Runtime Environment (JRE).

JVM tool interface.

JVM provides definitions for the:
Instruction Set (Central Processing Unit (CPU))
Register set
Class file format
Runtime stack
Garbage–collected head
Memory area
Fatal error reporting mechanism
High –precision timing support

Garbage collection has the following characteristics:
Check for and frees memory no longer needed, automatically.
Provides a system-level thread to track memory allocation.

The JVM does the following three main tasks:
Loads code: performed by the class loader.
Verifies code: performed by the byte code verifies.
Executes code: performed by the runtime interface.

There are the following five primary workflows of a software developing project:

Requirement capturing, analysis, design, implementation, and testing.

Abstraction, means ignoring the non-essential details of an object and concentrating on its essential details.

Encapsulation provides data representation flexibility, by hiding the implementation details of a class.  It loads all the classes necessary, for the execution of the program.

Maintains classes of the local file system, in a separate namespace.

Avoids execution of the program whose byte code has been changed illegally.

Example with a simple Java program

Open Notepad and type in this program, maintaining the upper and lower case, because Java is a case-sensitive programming language.</string>

</resources>